<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Asia &#8211; John Flatley</title>
	<atom:link href="./index.html" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>./../../../index.html</link>
	<description>Become who you are</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2015 00:06:23 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.1.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Tips for traveling abroad</title>
		<link>./../../../2015/06/tips-for-traveling-abroad/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../../../2015/06/tips-for-traveling-abroad/index.html#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[John Flatley]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2015 00:05:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=333</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>After traveling throughout Asia and Europe the past few months I decided to share some tips on how I was able to do it on a budget and avoid inconveniences like buying separate sim cards each place I went. 1. Use flight deal sites to find the best price and be patient. Part of traveling on [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2015/06/tips-for-traveling-abroad/index.html">Tips for traveling abroad</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">John Flatley</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>After traveling throughout Asia and Europe the past few months I decided to share some tips on how I was able to do it on a budget and avoid inconveniences like buying separate sim cards each place I went.<span id="more-333"></span></p>
<p><strong>1. Use flight deal sites to find the best price and be patient.</strong></p>
<p>Part of traveling on a budget involves patience and scouring flight deal sites. I don&#8217;t mean orbitz/kayak/expedia. I&#8217;m not a big fan of those because you often don&#8217;t get to choose your seats. I like to use www.theflightdeal.com and www.secretflying.com. Between these two sites I was able to book my trip to Hong Kong/Shanghai/Tokyo for $675 and to Stockholm for $600.</p>
<p><strong>2. Get Global Entry and <strong>TSA Pre<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/2714.png" alt="✔" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />.</strong></strong></p>
<p>There&#8217;s nothing I hate more than waiting in lines. With Global Entry and TSA Pre<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/2714.png" alt="✔" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> you&#8217;ll get to coast through the security and immigration lines in the U.S. Also, you don&#8217;t have to take all your clothes off or remove your electronics just to go through security. My advice, get Global Entry. It&#8217;s $100 for five years and you get TSA Pre<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/2714.png" alt="✔" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> for free.</p>
<p><strong>3. Use Scandinavia as a gateway to Europe.</strong></p>
<p>Traveling to Europe can be expensive, especially during the summer. If you&#8217;re lucky enough to live in San Francisco, Orlando, or Los Angeles you can often find super cheap flights in and out of Oslo or Stockholm on Norwegian. By super cheap I mean $350 round trip cheap. Other airlines also provide cheap flights in an out of those cities, but I wouldn&#8217;t recommend staying there too long. Both Oslo and Stockholm are extremely expensive, but you can find cheap flights to the major cities in Europe.</p>
<p><strong>4. Stay at an Airbnb over hotels.</strong></p>
<p>I&#8217;ve gotten over the age where I want to stay at a hostel. Sure they&#8217;re fun and you get to meet a lot of people, but when I&#8217;m traveling with a significant other I just want to have my own room. I used to be a fan of www.hotwire.com to find good deals on hotels, but now I&#8217;m finding Airbnb is a much better option. They are cheaper than a hotel, have more amenities like a refrigerator, and if you get lucky you may get one where you meet your host and can get some local guidance on where to eat and go out. So far I haven&#8217;t had a bad experience, but I also only book rooms with someone who has plenty of positive reviews.</p>
<p><strong>5. Get T-Mobile.</strong></p>
<p>One of the inconveniences of traveling abroad is cell service. In many countries you can get by with using internet at bars and cafes, but why risk it? T-mobile has free international roaming. I visited five different countries in Europe and didn&#8217;t have to bother buying a separate sim card each place I went. If you&#8217;re not on T-Mobile, you can often find a deal on their website for a $.99 sim card and ask a friend to add them to your family plan. It ended up being $30 with activation and taxes, but it beat buying a $15 &#8211; $30 sim card each place we went.</p>
<p>Although the data roaming is free, the speed is throttled. Even with the speeds throttled, I was still able to navigate using Google maps, search local places, upload photos to snapchat and using a messaging app like WhatsApp. What else could you really need abroad?</p>
<p><strong>6. Buy your museum tickets ahead of time.</strong></p>
<p>Most attractions you&#8217;ll want to visit will require a ticket. If you&#8217;re traveling through Europe I highly recommend you purchase them ahead of time. Places like the Vatican Museums, Colosseum, and Anne Frank&#8217;s house consistently have long lines. However, if you purchase your tickets ahead of time you can bypass the line.</p>
<p><strong>7. Get a Charles Schwab checking account.</strong></p>
<p>There&#8217;s nothing I hate more than paying a fee that I don&#8217;t have to, especially when it comes to converting money. Any time you exchange cash for another currency you&#8217;re getting screwed, unless you&#8217;re in Argentina and you&#8217;re trading it to someone on the street. One time I exchanged $300 in Berlin and received the equivalent of $240 in euros. My best advice is to get a Charles Schwab checking account and take money out of an ATM once you&#8217;ve landed at your destination. Charles Schwab refunds any ATM fees and will give you the best conversion rate.</p>
<p><b>8. Get a credit card with no foreign transaction fees.</b></p>
<p>Like I said before, I hate paying unnecessary fees. Most credit card companies charge a 3% foreign transaction fee. There are plenty of choices out there for fee free cards, but most charge a yearly fee. I carry a Barclaycard Arrival Plus card but I have many friends that like the Chase Sapphire Preferred card. Barclay also has a no fee version of it&#8217;s card but gives you less points per dollar. I would recommend during some research online to see which one fits your needs bests.</p>
<p><strong>9. Use The Man in Seat 61 for your train itinerary.</strong></p>
<p>If you&#8217;re traveling through Europe by train it can get a bit daunting to figure out the best way to get around. I found www.seat61.com to be the best resource on the web. This site gives you multiple options for how to get to a destination and links you directly to the travel site to book your tickets. I wouldn&#8217;t have known about the <a href="./../../../2015/06/bernina-express/index.html">Bernina Express</a> had I not used this site. Like booking a flight, be patient as there&#8217;s usually deals on train tickets where you can get first class tickets for only a few more dollars than second class.</p>
<p><strong>10. Don&#8217;t plan everything you&#8217;ll do.</strong></p>
<p>I&#8217;m the type of person that has to have everything planned. Many of you aren&#8217;t like that and I applaud you. However, if you&#8217;re like me and have to plan everything out, try to leave some space for the unexpected. I had planned our transportation, housing, and wrote down some sites we wanted to see in Europe but let the environment dictate what we did. If we saw a cool street we wanted to walk down, we did it. If there was a cute square where we wanted to sit and have a drink, we did it. We couldn&#8217;t have done this if we had had a strict time table, so leave some time for the unexpected.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2015/06/tips-for-traveling-abroad/index.html">Tips for traveling abroad</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">John Flatley</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../../../2015/06/tips-for-traveling-abroad/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Kawaii!</title>
		<link>./../../../2015/05/kawaii/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../../../2015/05/kawaii/index.html#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[John Flatley]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2015 03:01:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=131</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Day 3 Our first item on the agenda for the day was food. Yao wanted to try okonomiyaki, a savory pancake with meat and vegetables added in. The place we went to had an all you can eat option, but we arrived late and didn&#8217;t know how to order. Based on the size of our neighbors&#8217; bowls, we [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2015/05/kawaii/index.html">Kawaii!</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">John Flatley</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Day 3<br />
Our first item on the agenda for the day was food. Yao wanted to try okonomiyaki, a savory pancake with meat and vegetables added in. The place we went to had an all you can eat option, but <span id="more-131"></span>we arrived late and didn&#8217;t know how to order. Based on the size of our neighbors&#8217; bowls, we ordered two bowls of pancake ingredients and a plate of noodles. In retrospect, our neighbors were probably enjoying the all-you-can-eat menu as our bowls were huge.</p>
<div id="attachment_144" style="width: 639px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/IMG_20150428_2311280031.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-144" decoding="async" class="size-large wp-image-144" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/IMG_20150428_2311280031-1024x576.jpg" alt="Precooked ingredients" width="629" height="354" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/IMG_20150428_2311280031-1024x576.jpg 1024w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/IMG_20150428_2311280031-300x169.jpg 300w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/IMG_20150428_2311280031-900x506.jpg 900w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/IMG_20150428_2311280031-1280x720.jpg 1280w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/IMG_20150428_2311280031.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 629px) 100vw, 629px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-144" class="wp-caption-text">Uncooked ingredients</p></div>
<p>Since we didn&#8217;t really  have any idea of what to do, we started spying on the people around us. The steps we were able to determine:</p>
<ol>
<li>Mix up the ingredients</li>
<li>Pour said ingredients on hot plate</li>
<li>Place meat on top of pancake</li>
<li>Flip after five minutes</li>
<li>Drizzle on some mayo and undetermined brown sauce on</li>
<li>Eat.</li>
</ol>
<div id="attachment_108" style="width: 639px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/IMG_20150428_232119085.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-108" decoding="async" class="size-large wp-image-108" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/IMG_20150428_232119085-1024x576.jpg" alt="Food cooking" width="629" height="354" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/IMG_20150428_232119085-1024x576.jpg 1024w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/IMG_20150428_232119085-300x169.jpg 300w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/IMG_20150428_232119085-900x506.jpg 900w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/IMG_20150428_232119085-1280x720.jpg 1280w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/IMG_20150428_232119085.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 629px) 100vw, 629px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-108" class="wp-caption-text">Food cooking</p></div>
<p>For some reason, ours seemed to be cooking way faster than everyone else&#8217;s. It was unclear if our plate was at a higher setting than everyone else&#8217;s, but we just ate it before it could burn.</p>
<div id="attachment_109" style="width: 639px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/IMG_20150428_232407789.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-109" decoding="async" class="wp-image-109 size-large" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/IMG_20150428_232407789-e1430615435713-1024x576.jpg" alt="Finished product" width="629" height="354" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/IMG_20150428_232407789-e1430615435713-1024x576.jpg 1024w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/IMG_20150428_232407789-e1430615435713-300x169.jpg 300w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/IMG_20150428_232407789-e1430615435713-900x506.jpg 900w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/IMG_20150428_232407789-e1430615435713-1280x720.jpg 1280w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/IMG_20150428_232407789-e1430615435713.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 629px) 100vw, 629px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-109" class="wp-caption-text">Finished product</p></div>
<p>Once we were half way done I did my best to mimic what I&#8217;d seen at Benihana to cook the noodles. Overall, I&#8217;d say the meal was pretty good, but we definitely got gypped. All the other tourists had the waitress do all the cooking for them.</p>
<p>Next, we walked over to Meiji Shrine. We made it just in time to go into the inner garden and see Kiyomasa’s Well. The walk to the pond and through the iris guardian was pretty relaxing, but the well itself was a bit anti-climatic. It&#8217;s just an opening to a spring that feeds the pond, not to mention the guard wouldn&#8217;t even let us drink from it. People continue to visit thinking it provides positive energy.</p>
<p>Before entering the shrine you&#8217;re supposed to cleanse yourself at a fountain by first pouring water over your left hand, then right, then drinking some water out of your left hand and spit into it the trough, then pour water over your hands again.</p>
<div id="attachment_123" style="width: 633px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/Snapchat-4407530445264769903.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-123" decoding="async" class="wp-image-123 size-large" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/Snapchat-4407530445264769903-623x1024.jpg" alt="Snapchat-4407530445264769903" width="623" height="1024" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/Snapchat-4407530445264769903-623x1024.jpg 623w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/Snapchat-4407530445264769903-182x300.jpg 182w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/Snapchat-4407530445264769903-900x1480.jpg 900w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/Snapchat-4407530445264769903.jpg 1080w" sizes="(max-width: 623px) 100vw, 623px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-123" class="wp-caption-text">Cleansing myself before entering the shrine</p></div>
<p>Within the shrine, you can pay your respect through an interesting ritual that Yao and I both performed. First you toss a coin into an offering box, bow twice, clap twice, pray with your hands still clasped, and then end by bowing once more. The entire experience was calming and serene.</p>
<p><a href="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/IMG_20150429_011254373_HDR.jpg"><img decoding="async" class="alignnone size-large wp-image-112" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/IMG_20150429_011254373_HDR-576x1024.jpg" alt="IMG_20150429_011254373_HDR" width="576" height="1024" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/IMG_20150429_011254373_HDR-576x1024.jpg 576w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/IMG_20150429_011254373_HDR-169x300.jpg 169w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/IMG_20150429_011254373_HDR-900x1600.jpg 900w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/IMG_20150429_011254373_HDR.jpg 1152w" sizes="(max-width: 576px) 100vw, 576px" /></a></p>
<p>After leaving the shrine we headed to Takeshita Dori. If Yodabashi Camera was sensory overload for electronics, this was sensory overload for teenage girls. I had never seen so many tweens in one location outside of a Jonas Brother&#8217;s concert. That&#8217;s a joke, but it really happened!</p>
<div id="attachment_124" style="width: 633px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/Snapchat-5416258789505442617.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-124" decoding="async" class="wp-image-124 size-large" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/Snapchat-5416258789505442617-623x1024.jpg" alt="Snapchat-5416258789505442617" width="623" height="1024" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/Snapchat-5416258789505442617-623x1024.jpg 623w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/Snapchat-5416258789505442617-182x300.jpg 182w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/Snapchat-5416258789505442617-900x1480.jpg 900w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/Snapchat-5416258789505442617.jpg 1080w" sizes="(max-width: 623px) 100vw, 623px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-124" class="wp-caption-text">Takeshita Dori</p></div>
<p>Takeshit Dori is pretty much a street lined with stores selling apparel for all the different teen fashions. Most of them are selling things like adult sized doll clothes or old victorian clothing. Girls that wear these types of clothes are going for the cute factor, not sexy. We didn&#8217;t spend much time there, but Yao and I did buy some pretty slick sunglasses.</p>
<div id="attachment_127" style="width: 633px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/Snapchat-6941804989862017295.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-127" decoding="async" class="size-large wp-image-127" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/Snapchat-6941804989862017295-623x1024.jpg" alt="Kawaii, or cute, fashion " width="623" height="1024" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/Snapchat-6941804989862017295-623x1024.jpg 623w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/Snapchat-6941804989862017295-182x300.jpg 182w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/Snapchat-6941804989862017295-900x1480.jpg 900w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/Snapchat-6941804989862017295.jpg 1080w" sizes="(max-width: 623px) 100vw, 623px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-127" class="wp-caption-text">Kawaii, or cute, fashion</p></div>
<p>At this point in the trip, ramen was the last thing we had to try before leaving. We tried to find Ippudo, a popular ramen-ya that garners multi-hour long waits in New York. Unfortunately, it was closed by the time we got there. Instead, we settled for some other ramen place where you have to order from a vending machine&#8211;a common ramen ordering &amp; payment system in Japan.</p>
<p>The machine doesn&#8217;t actually make you the ramen. It just prints out a receipt for whatever you ordered. At the machine you get to choose what type of ramen you want as well as any extras  you might want such as pork or egg. Yao ordered the most expensive ramen assuming it was the best, but it was really just the same as the other choices with an extra order of noodles. This place also let you customize everything about the ingredients: firmness of the noodles, broth spiciness, amount of garlic, etc.</p>
<div id="attachment_121" style="width: 633px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/Snapchat-777300701902053279.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-121" decoding="async" class="size-large wp-image-121" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/Snapchat-777300701902053279-623x1024.jpg" alt="Ordering ramen from a vending machine" width="623" height="1024" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/Snapchat-777300701902053279-623x1024.jpg 623w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/Snapchat-777300701902053279-182x300.jpg 182w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/Snapchat-777300701902053279-900x1480.jpg 900w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/Snapchat-777300701902053279.jpg 1080w" sizes="(max-width: 623px) 100vw, 623px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-121" class="wp-caption-text">Ordering ramen from a vending machine</p></div>
<p>Seating inside the ramen-ya was like the cubbies you find in a college library. Everyone had their own eating cubby with panels to block them from the people sitting next them. The kitchen was in the middle so you couldn&#8217;t see across to the other people. This was ideal for me since I always feel like people are judging me for my slurping and profuse sweating resulting from the spicy broth.</p>
<p>To actually get your food, you&#8217;d ring the buzzer and place your order slips at the edge of table. After about 5 minutes, one of the cooks would pass your food through the window in front of you. I&#8217;d say that overall, the ramen was better than what you&#8217;ll find in the states, but not by much. However, the experience was more enjoyable and the service was way faster.</p>
<div id="attachment_122" style="width: 639px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/Snapchat-3417845027658553352.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-122" decoding="async" class="wp-image-122 size-large" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/Snapchat-3417845027658553352-e1430617313221-1024x616.jpg" alt="Spicy ramen" width="629" height="378" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/Snapchat-3417845027658553352-e1430617313221-1024x616.jpg 1024w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/Snapchat-3417845027658553352-e1430617313221-300x181.jpg 300w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/Snapchat-3417845027658553352-e1430617313221-900x542.jpg 900w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/Snapchat-3417845027658553352-e1430617313221-1280x771.jpg 1280w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/Snapchat-3417845027658553352-e1430617313221.jpg 1794w" sizes="(max-width: 629px) 100vw, 629px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-122" class="wp-caption-text">Spicy ramen</p></div>
<p>On the way back to our room I was solicited by a very nice gentleman for &#8220;a happy ending, or whatever I want(ed).&#8221; Unfortunately for them, I was only in the mood for a happy beginning.</p>
<p>Day 4<br />
On our last day we didn&#8217;t have much time before we needed to head to the airport so we made a quick stop by Akasusa. I had been wondering the whole trip where the tourist area was and we found it. There are tons of shops selling souvenirs and food stands with fried food. Yao and I bought some fried buns with fruit filling, which turned out to be more like fried mochi.</p>
<p><a href="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/IMG_20150429_183158348_HDR.jpg"><img decoding="async" class="alignnone size-large wp-image-113" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/IMG_20150429_183158348_HDR-1024x576.jpg" alt="IMG_20150429_183158348_HDR" width="629" height="354" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/IMG_20150429_183158348_HDR-1024x576.jpg 1024w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/IMG_20150429_183158348_HDR-300x169.jpg 300w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/IMG_20150429_183158348_HDR-900x506.jpg 900w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/IMG_20150429_183158348_HDR-1280x720.jpg 1280w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/IMG_20150429_183158348_HDR.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 629px) 100vw, 629px" /></a></p>
<p>There&#8217;s also a shrine similar to the one we had seen the other day. We passed on paying our respects but still walked around for a bit. I did find it weird that for such a touristy area nothing was in English.</p>
<div id="attachment_114" style="width: 639px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/IMG_20150429_183409030_HDR.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-114" decoding="async" class="size-large wp-image-114" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/IMG_20150429_183409030_HDR-1024x576.jpg" alt="Shrine in Asakusa" width="629" height="354" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/IMG_20150429_183409030_HDR-1024x576.jpg 1024w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/IMG_20150429_183409030_HDR-300x169.jpg 300w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/IMG_20150429_183409030_HDR-900x506.jpg 900w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/IMG_20150429_183409030_HDR-1280x720.jpg 1280w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/IMG_20150429_183409030_HDR.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 629px) 100vw, 629px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-114" class="wp-caption-text">Shrine in Asakusa</p></div>
<p>For our last meal we decided to grab ramen again. Luckily, there was an Ippudo two blocks from where we were staying. We must have arrived right when they opened because there was only a few people seated. Unlike the ramen place from the previous night, the seating was more communal around a large rectangular table and we ordered from a menu. Also, they used tonkotsu broth, but it was just as good as the ramen from the night before.</p>
<div id="attachment_126" style="width: 639px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/Snapchat-5959930857970517051.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-126" decoding="async" class="wp-image-126 size-large" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/Snapchat-5959930857970517051-e1430618924483-1024x616.jpg" alt="Ramen from Ippudo" width="629" height="378" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/Snapchat-5959930857970517051-e1430618924483-1024x616.jpg 1024w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/Snapchat-5959930857970517051-e1430618924483-300x181.jpg 300w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/Snapchat-5959930857970517051-e1430618924483-900x542.jpg 900w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/Snapchat-5959930857970517051-e1430618924483-1280x771.jpg 1280w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/Snapchat-5959930857970517051-e1430618924483.jpg 1794w" sizes="(max-width: 629px) 100vw, 629px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-126" class="wp-caption-text">Ramen from Ippudo</p></div>
<p>Although my chopsticks skills improved on the trip, they still didn&#8217;t stack up against the locals. Three businessmen sat day after Yao and I had gotten our food and finished well before we did. It was then that I realized that ramen is pretty much Japanese fast food.</p>
<div id="attachment_117" style="width: 639px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/IMG_20150429_195939326.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-117" decoding="async" class="wp-image-117 size-large" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/IMG_20150429_195939326-1024x576.jpg" alt="Ramen at Ippudo" width="629" height="354" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/IMG_20150429_195939326-1024x576.jpg 1024w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/IMG_20150429_195939326-300x169.jpg 300w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/IMG_20150429_195939326-900x506.jpg 900w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/IMG_20150429_195939326-1280x720.jpg 1280w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/IMG_20150429_195939326.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 629px) 100vw, 629px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-117" class="wp-caption-text">Communal style eating</p></div>
<p>Like the Mission in San Francisco, most places in Japan are cash only. At this point, Yao and I are down to our last few thousand Yen. We had just enough cash based on the price on the menu. However, some places in Tokyo list the price with tax include and others without. Unfortunately for us, Ippudo lists it without. Yao and I take turns leaving to try to find an ATM that would accept foreign ATM cards, but we kept getting denied. Eventually, Yao was able to grab money out of a Family Mart back by our apartment, allowing us to pay an hour later.</p>
<p>We flew United home , which once again had terrible food. Also, for some reason, they decided to melt their butter which I accidentally spilled into my lap. Luckily, I had a spare pair of gym shorts in my bag to change into. I apparently wasn&#8217;t the only victim since I saw multiple people walking around with butter stains on their shirts.</p>
<p>Upon landing, I got to try out Global Entry for the first time. It wasn&#8217;t as gratifying as I was hoping it would be because the line for customs was really short. Nevertheless, all I had to do was scan my passport, answer some customs questions, scan my fingers and I was done.</p>
<p>Overall, this has been one of the best trips I&#8217;ve ever been on. I met new people, experienced new cultures, saw some iconic landmarks, and most importantly, ate amazing food!</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2015/05/kawaii/index.html">Kawaii!</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">John Flatley</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../../../2015/05/kawaii/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Land of the rising sun</title>
		<link>./../../../2015/05/land-of-the-rising-sun/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../../../2015/05/land-of-the-rising-sun/index.html#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[John Flatley]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2015 16:02:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=94</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>I got a bit lazy while in Tokyo and decided to wait to post my updates until I was back in the states and over my jet lag. Before I get into everything we did, I want to comment on Tokyo in general. If I could describe it in one word it would be orderly. The city [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2015/05/land-of-the-rising-sun/index.html">Land of the rising sun</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">John Flatley</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I got a bit lazy while in Tokyo and decided to wait to post my updates until I was back in the states and over my jet lag. Before I get into everything we did, I want to comment on Tokyo in general. If I could describe it in one word it would be orderly.<span id="more-94"></span> The city itself is impeccably clean despite having a confusing recycling system (combustibles, non-combustibles, recyclables, possibly three more). The people are by far the most respectful and polite in the world. They stick to the correct side of the sidewalk, respect your personal space, wait for everyone to get off the subway before entering, and either bow or thank you after ever encounter.</p>
<p>Day 1</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><a href="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/IMG_20150426_225648582.jpg"><img decoding="async" class=" size-medium wp-image-101 alignleft" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/IMG_20150426_225648582-169x300.jpg" alt="IMG_20150426_225648582" width="169" height="300" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/IMG_20150426_225648582-169x300.jpg 169w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/IMG_20150426_225648582-576x1024.jpg 576w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/IMG_20150426_225648582-900x1600.jpg 900w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/IMG_20150426_225648582.jpg 1152w" sizes="(max-width: 169px) 100vw, 169px" /></a></p>
<p>Unfortunately for me, the meal on our ANA flight to Tokyo consisted of all fish. As a result, when we landed we decided to grab some vending machine ice cream. I got something that was similar to an ice cream sandwich, but was enclosed in wafer and was pretty good. Yao got a donut, which became a common theme on the trip. We decided to take the local line into the city because we wanted the authentic experience and were being cheap. I embraced the Japanese culture and slept the whole way. Seriously, everyone one on the subway is sleeping. I don&#8217;t know how they don&#8217;t miss their stops.</p>
<p>Our Airbnb was in Roppongi, which is notorious for it&#8217;s night life. The room was tiny and the bathroom looked like it was from a cruise ship. I probably had 2&#8243; of clearance from the ceiling.</p>
<p><a href="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/IMG_20150427_011403646.jpg"><img decoding="async" class="alignnone wp-image-128 size-large" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/IMG_20150427_011403646-1024x576.jpg" alt="IMG_20150427_011403646" width="629" height="354" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/IMG_20150427_011403646-1024x576.jpg 1024w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/IMG_20150427_011403646-300x169.jpg 300w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/IMG_20150427_011403646-900x506.jpg 900w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/IMG_20150427_011403646-1280x720.jpg 1280w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/IMG_20150427_011403646.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 629px) 100vw, 629px" /></a></p>
<p>After getting settled, we went exploring for some teppanyaki. The first place we stopped at denied us because we didn&#8217;t have a reservation. We ended up at place that was &#8220;affordable&#8221; according to a Google Maps review. I&#8217;m not sure how expensive dinner usually is in Tokyo, but this was one the of most expensive meals I had every paid for and didn&#8217;t get much food. Nonetheless, the meal was delicious. I got a sirloin that came with a mix of pink salt and wasabi. Also, I should note that this wasn&#8217;t Benihana&#8217;s teppanyaki with shrimp flying through the air, but I was pretty impressed by the chef&#8217;s attention to detail.</p>
<div id="attachment_99" style="width: 192px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><a href="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/wpid-wp-1430521714593.jpeg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-99" decoding="async" class="wp-image-99 size-medium" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/wpid-wp-1430521714593-182x300.jpeg" alt="wpid-wp-1430521714593.jpeg" width="182" height="300" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/wpid-wp-1430521714593-182x300.jpeg 182w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/wpid-wp-1430521714593-623x1024.jpeg 623w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/wpid-wp-1430521714593-900x1480.jpeg 900w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/wpid-wp-1430521714593.jpeg 1080w" sizes="(max-width: 182px) 100vw, 182px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-99" class="wp-caption-text">Hoppy</p></div>
<p>We ended the night by grabbing cheap drinks and food at a local izakaya. Yao order something called &#8220;Hoppy&#8221; that had two choices, inside or outside. We had no clue what it was, but the waitress came out with a glass half filled with a clear liquid and a bottle of Hoppy.</p>
<p>We later found out it was sochu and a poor man&#8217;s beer that you&#8217;re supposed to mix together. The combo didn&#8217;t taste like much so as we drank we continued to poor in more Hoppy trying to give it flavor, but we felt like we were doing it wrong. The guy next to us ordered some as well and we decided to watch and learn, a common theme on this part of the trip. We had been doing it wrong. Apparently, you&#8217;re only supposed to pour the Hoppy in once, and save it for your next round.</p>
<div id="attachment_98" style="width: 192px" class="wp-caption alignright"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-98" decoding="async" class="wp-image-98 size-medium" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/wpid-wp-1430521710323-182x300.jpeg" alt="wpid-wp-1430521710323.jpeg" width="182" height="300" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/wpid-wp-1430521710323-182x300.jpeg 182w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/wpid-wp-1430521710323-623x1024.jpeg 623w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/wpid-wp-1430521710323-900x1480.jpeg 900w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/wpid-wp-1430521710323.jpeg 1080w" sizes="(max-width: 182px) 100vw, 182px" /><p id="caption-attachment-98" class="wp-caption-text">Fried sardine spine</p></div>
<p>We had been trying to make small talk with the cook and he must have found it funny how we were watching everyone around us because he decided to give us a complimentary plate of fried sardine spine. He kept motioning to us to eat it and at this point I thought he was trolling us. We went to our go-to guy next to us and he was chomping away at it, so we figured we had to try it. It pretty much tasted like you&#8217;d expect: crunchy, fishy, and salty. To say thanks we bought him a glass of Hoppy, our new favorite drink.</p>
<p>Day 2<br />
If you&#8217;re ever going to Tokyo, you&#8217;ll probably be told to go to the early morning <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wEltG-T6-zo">fish auction</a> at Tsukiji Market. Yao and I decided to pass on the auction since you have to get there at 4:30am, but still headed over to grab breakfast sushi. Two well known places are Sushi Dai and Daiwa Sushi. It&#8217;s pretty easy to find them since there&#8217;s always a line of 100+ people, which we stood in until we realized it was only for Sushi Dai. We opted for Daiwa Sushi, which was only a 20 minute wait.</p>
<p>This was by far the best sushi I&#8217;ve ever had. There was a set menu with multiple courses. My favorite had to be either the fatty tuna, shrimp or uni. All three had a great creamy texture, no fishy taste, and you could tell were fresh from the sea. The more interesting item was the shrimp head that had a sort of creamy and crunchy texture.</p>
<div id="attachment_103" style="width: 639px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/IMG_20150427_144029539.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-103" decoding="async" class="wp-image-103 size-large" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/IMG_20150427_144029539-1024x576.jpg" alt="IMG_20150427_144029539" width="629" height="354" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/IMG_20150427_144029539-1024x576.jpg 1024w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/IMG_20150427_144029539-300x169.jpg 300w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/IMG_20150427_144029539-900x506.jpg 900w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/IMG_20150427_144029539-1280x720.jpg 1280w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/IMG_20150427_144029539.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 629px) 100vw, 629px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-103" class="wp-caption-text">Sushi rolls, shrimp head, yellow tail, medium fatty tuna</p></div>
<p>After taking a quick nap, we headed to the Google office in the Mori Tower for lunch. I was hoping to grab a picture of Mount Fuji, but it was hazy and I couldn&#8217;t see further than a few miles.</p>
<p>Next, we headed to the Imperial Palace. It reminded me a lot of London where something old, like the Tower of London, is sitting in the middle of a modern city.</p>
<p><a href="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/IMG_20150427_230017636_HDR.jpg"><img decoding="async" class="alignnone size-large wp-image-104" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/IMG_20150427_230017636_HDR-1024x576.jpg" alt="IMG_20150427_230017636_HDR" width="629" height="354" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/IMG_20150427_230017636_HDR-1024x576.jpg 1024w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/IMG_20150427_230017636_HDR-300x169.jpg 300w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/IMG_20150427_230017636_HDR-900x506.jpg 900w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/IMG_20150427_230017636_HDR-1280x720.jpg 1280w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/IMG_20150427_230017636_HDR.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 629px) 100vw, 629px" /></a></p>
<p>We walked around the gardens for a while, which was pretty relaxing. The entire time we were trying to figure out how to get to see where the imperial family actually lives, and after about an hour looking we found out you have to be on a guided tour to visit the grounds. At least I got this picture out in front of the Meganebashi Bridge which is an entrance to the inner palace grounds</p>
<div id="attachment_110" style="width: 639px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/IMG_20150428_240438572_HDR.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-110" decoding="async" class="wp-image-110 size-large" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/IMG_20150428_240438572_HDR-1024x576.jpg" alt="Meganebashi Bridge" width="629" height="354" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/IMG_20150428_240438572_HDR-1024x576.jpg 1024w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/IMG_20150428_240438572_HDR-300x169.jpg 300w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/IMG_20150428_240438572_HDR-900x506.jpg 900w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/IMG_20150428_240438572_HDR-1280x720.jpg 1280w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/IMG_20150428_240438572_HDR.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 629px) 100vw, 629px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-110" class="wp-caption-text">Meganebashi Bridge</p></div>
<p>Our next stop was Shibuya, which is the fashion center of Tokyo and hotspot for young people. We stopped by the famous scramble crossing, Shibuya Crossing, but it wasn&#8217;t as epic as I was expecting. You definitely see a lot of people crossing, but it didn&#8217;t feel extraordinary. The fashion in Shibuya is a stark contrast from Roppongi where everyone is wearing a suit. You see Brooklyn hipsters, Venice beach skaters, southern belles, goths, etc. Some girls dressed like they were a doll or anime character.</p>
<div id="attachment_111" style="width: 639px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/IMG_20150428_244102328.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-111" decoding="async" class="wp-image-111 size-large" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/IMG_20150428_244102328-1024x576.jpg" alt="IMG_20150428_244102328" width="629" height="354" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/IMG_20150428_244102328-1024x576.jpg 1024w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/IMG_20150428_244102328-300x169.jpg 300w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/IMG_20150428_244102328-900x506.jpg 900w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/IMG_20150428_244102328-1280x720.jpg 1280w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/IMG_20150428_244102328.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 629px) 100vw, 629px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-111" class="wp-caption-text">Shibuya Crossing</p></div>
<p>Later, we walked down some alleys near Harajuku Street and I felt like I was in southern California. There are tons of shops selling thrifty american clothes, everyone looks like a skater, and the restaurants have a California vibe. We stopped by a coffee shop so that Yao could get a hipster donut with passion fruit frosting. By the way, Yao literally had to stop at any place that was selling donuts. By the end he had bought donuts from Dunkin Donuts, a vending machine, this hipster donut shop, and Krispy Kreme. I stopped at The Great Burger and kind of felt bad for eating american food while in Japan, but there were zero tourists there. Everyone seemed to be a local and it made for some great people watching.</p>
<p>We made a quick stop in Akihabara, electronics central. Nabil had recommended we stop by Yodabashi camera, a huge electronics department store, to look for cheap camera parts. The amount of ads and videos in this place could lead to sensory overload. I found it funny that one of the floors was solely dedicated to models, like Gundams, and was filled with middle aged men. Unfortunately, even with the weakened Yen and discounts, it still wasn&#8217;t cheaper to buy anything.</p>
<div id="attachment_106" style="width: 639px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/IMG_20150428_032750657.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-106" decoding="async" class="wp-image-106 size-large" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/IMG_20150428_032750657-1024x576.jpg" alt="IMG_20150428_032750657" width="629" height="354" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/IMG_20150428_032750657-1024x576.jpg 1024w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/IMG_20150428_032750657-300x169.jpg 300w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/IMG_20150428_032750657-900x506.jpg 900w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/IMG_20150428_032750657-1280x720.jpg 1280w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/05/IMG_20150428_032750657.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 629px) 100vw, 629px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-106" class="wp-caption-text">Yodabashi Camera</p></div>
<p>Later in the night we met up with Yao&#8217;s friend Jia who he used to play ultimate with in the states. Jia took us out clubbing, Tokyo style, which was pretty much like clubbing in the states. TL;DR club going up on a Tuesday, models and bottles, master chief, pitbull on loop, EDM til our ears bleed, giving a literal meaning to the land of the rising sun.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2015/05/land-of-the-rising-sun/index.html">Land of the rising sun</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">John Flatley</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../../../2015/05/land-of-the-rising-sun/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Love, true love</title>
		<link>./../../../2015/04/love-true-love/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../../../2015/04/love-true-love/index.html#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[John Flatley]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2015 09:05:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=81</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Shanghai Day 2: After grabbing breakfast at a nearby Singaporean restaurant, Yao and I headed to Cheng Huang Miao (City God Temple). The temple and nearby Yu Garden were beautiful with their traditional architecture, but it was a bit too touristy. There were thousands of people walking around the shops and restaurants. Yao and I [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2015/04/love-true-love/index.html">Love, true love</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">John Flatley</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong><u>Shanghai Day 2:</u></strong><br />
After grabbing breakfast at a nearby Singaporean restaurant, Yao and I headed to Cheng Huang Miao (City God Temple). The temple and nearby Yu Garden were beautiful with their traditional architecture, but <span id="more-81"></span>it was a bit too touristy. There were thousands of people walking around the shops and restaurants.</p>
<div id="attachment_87" style="width: 633px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/04/wpid-wp-1430125826074.jpeg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-87" decoding="async" class="size-large wp-image-87" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/04/wpid-wp-1430125826074-623x1024.jpeg" alt="Cheng Huang Miao" width="623" height="1024" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/04/wpid-wp-1430125826074-623x1024.jpeg 623w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/04/wpid-wp-1430125826074-182x300.jpeg 182w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/04/wpid-wp-1430125826074-900x1480.jpeg 900w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/04/wpid-wp-1430125826074.jpeg 1080w" sizes="(max-width: 623px) 100vw, 623px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-87" class="wp-caption-text">Cheng Huang Miao</p></div>
<p>Yao and I decided to pass on the tourist restaurants in favor of local street food. I hadn&#8217;t gotten too harassed on the trip so far, but as we walked along the food stands I was constantly being jabbed at with skewers of grilled squid and meat. We ordered some sheng jian bao (fried soup dumplings) and shanghai style noodles, but both were pretty disappointing. The dumplings were cold with no soup inside them and the noodles didn&#8217;t have any flavor. One of the more interesting things Yao bought was stinky tofu. There&#8217;s no other word to describe the smell other than pungent.</p>
<div id="attachment_71" style="width: 639px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/04/wpid-wp-1430064329996.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-71" decoding="async" class="size-large wp-image-71" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/04/wpid-wp-1430064329996-1024x576.jpg" alt="Local alley with street food" width="629" height="354" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/04/wpid-wp-1430064329996-1024x576.jpg 1024w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/04/wpid-wp-1430064329996-300x169.jpg 300w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/04/wpid-wp-1430064329996-900x506.jpg 900w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/04/wpid-wp-1430064329996-1280x720.jpg 1280w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/04/wpid-wp-1430064329996.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 629px) 100vw, 629px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-71" class="wp-caption-text">Local alley with street food</p></div>
<p>We continued to walk around and buy some more souvenirs. One lady asked how much I paid Yao to translate for me. Another kept calling him little boy. I found it pretty funny, but I guess it should be expected when a Chinese guy is speaking to vendors in Mandarin and to his white friend in English.</p>
<p>One thing you quickly notice in Shanghai is the number of jobs that would seem superfluous in the US. For example, they have pedestrian enforcers who try make sure you stand on the curb while the crossing light is red. In the subways, they have security who try to block people from entering until they put their bag through an xray machine. I keep saying &#8220;try&#8221; because none of these positions have any authority. On the way back, I saw two guys walk right through a security man&#8217;s arm who was trying to block them. Another woman told her husband not to bother putting his bag on the belt because it didn&#8217;t matter.</p>
<p>Later that night we met up for dinner with some of Yao&#8217;s teammates from Clash of Clans to discuss some important things like if they should kick out some high school members and how. Despite it topic being a bit childish, it was fun to meet some more people and a big reason why traveling with Yao has been so much fun. Generally, I&#8217;m pretty shy and have trouble talking with people I don&#8217;t know, but having a common friend makes it a lot easier. In the end the inducted me into their clan, Smog Heaven.</p>
<div id="attachment_72" style="width: 639px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/04/wpid-wp-1430064352071.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-72" decoding="async" class="size-large wp-image-72" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/04/wpid-wp-1430064352071-1024x576.jpg" alt="tim (Tim), IamHORRIBLE (Yao), The Undertaker (Yuming) disussing important clan stuff" width="629" height="354" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/04/wpid-wp-1430064352071-1024x576.jpg 1024w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/04/wpid-wp-1430064352071-300x169.jpg 300w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/04/wpid-wp-1430064352071-900x506.jpg 900w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/04/wpid-wp-1430064352071-1280x720.jpg 1280w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/04/wpid-wp-1430064352071.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 629px) 100vw, 629px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-72" class="wp-caption-text">tim (Tim), IamHORRIBLE (Yao), and The Undertaker (Yuming) disussing important clan stuff</p></div>
<p><u><strong>Shanghai Day 3:</strong></u><br />
Yao and I started the day getting more soup dumplings. I think my count for the trip was 40, but I wish it were higher.</p>
<div id="attachment_63" style="width: 639px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/04/wpid-wp-1429980107439-e1429980423574.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-63" decoding="async" class="size-large wp-image-63" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/04/wpid-wp-1429980107439-e1429980423574-1024x616.jpg" alt="Boiled XLBs" width="629" height="378" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/04/wpid-wp-1429980107439-e1429980423574-1024x616.jpg 1024w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/04/wpid-wp-1429980107439-e1429980423574-300x181.jpg 300w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/04/wpid-wp-1429980107439-e1429980423574-900x542.jpg 900w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/04/wpid-wp-1429980107439-e1429980423574-1280x771.jpg 1280w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/04/wpid-wp-1429980107439-e1429980423574.jpg 1794w" sizes="(max-width: 629px) 100vw, 629px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-63" class="wp-caption-text">Boiled XLBs</p></div>
<p>Afterwards, we made a quick stop at a local temple, Jing An Shi, and walked around a nearby park. We saw one guy writing in calligraphy on the sidewalk with what looked like a huge paint brush attached to a bottle of water. We also came across some elderly men playing card games and gambling. Despite cultural and geographic differences, it was exactly like seeing people in Miami playing dominos or in New York playing chess.</p>
<p><a href="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/04/wpid-wp-1430125777826.jpeg"><img decoding="async" class="  aligncenter" style="width: 442px; max-width: 1080px;" title="wpid-wp-1430125777826.jpeg" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/04/wpid-wp-1430125777826.jpeg?w=1080" alt="image" height="724" /></a></p>
<p>The thing I was most excited to do that day and since we landed in Shanghai was to visit the marriage market. Traditionally in China, parents would set up their children with their future spouse. One way they did this was by posting spec sheets about their child like age, weight, height, income, etc at a local park. Generally, they would post the on an open umbrella that they set on the ground. They would also include what their requirements were for a spouse. For men, you better own a house and car or you have no chance. The children generally don&#8217;t approve of their parents doing this and rarely come to the market.</p>
<div id="attachment_74" style="width: 586px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/04/wpid-wp-1430064497907.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-74" decoding="async" class="size-large wp-image-74" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/04/wpid-wp-1430064497907-576x1024.jpg" alt="Dating spec sheets" width="576" height="1024" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/04/wpid-wp-1430064497907-576x1024.jpg 576w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/04/wpid-wp-1430064497907-169x300.jpg 169w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/04/wpid-wp-1430064497907-900x1600.jpg 900w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/04/wpid-wp-1430064497907.jpg 1152w" sizes="(max-width: 576px) 100vw, 576px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-74" class="wp-caption-text">Dating spec sheets</p></div>
<p>Despite living in the 21st century and the invention of online dating, these marriage markets still exist and I had to visit one. We headed to People&#8217;s Square and started walking around the park trying to find the market. I had no clue what I was looking for, but all if a sudden I started to see groups of elderly people crowded around umbrellas with postings on them. I knew we had found it but did not expect the number listings and people. There had to be thousands of people walking around trying to find their child a spouse. Guys carried around black books writing down phone numbers and specs. Mothers and fathers sat idly by their umbrella waiting for someone to come by. However, the most interesting thing is that 99% of the listings don&#8217;t have any pictures.</p>
<div id="attachment_85" style="width: 639px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/04/wpid-wp-1430125683355.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-85" decoding="async" class="wp-image-85 size-large" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/04/wpid-wp-1430125683355-1024x576.jpg" alt="wpid-wp-1430125683355.jpg" width="629" height="354" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/04/wpid-wp-1430125683355-1024x576.jpg 1024w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/04/wpid-wp-1430125683355-300x169.jpg 300w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/04/wpid-wp-1430125683355-900x506.jpg 900w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/04/wpid-wp-1430125683355-1280x720.jpg 1280w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/04/wpid-wp-1430125683355.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 629px) 100vw, 629px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-85" class="wp-caption-text">Multiply this scene by 100 to get an idea of how many people were there</p></div>
<p>The last thing I had to try before leaving China was hotpot. Luckily, we decided to get half normal broth and half spicy broth because the spicy one literally numbed my lips. I got a little worried during the meal when I realized I had been drinking tap water and my fears amplified when we saw a dog run through the restaurant.</p>
<p><a href="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/04/wpid-wp-1430068267178.jpeg"><img decoding="async" class="  aligncenter" style="width: 492px; max-width: 2000px;" title="wpid-wp-1430068267178.jpeg" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/04/wpid-wp-1430068267178.jpeg?w=2000" alt="image" height="345" /></a></p>
<p>On our way to grab drinks we say a woman making street noodles. At this point I figure I&#8217;m going to get sick for sure and might as well try them. Not to mention, Shanghai had to redeem itself for bad ones from the prior day. I&#8217;m not sure what she did differently, but I loved them. They had way more flavor and complexity than the ones from before.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2015/04/love-true-love/index.html">Love, true love</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">John Flatley</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../../../2015/04/love-true-love/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Behind the Great Firewall</title>
		<link>./../../../2015/04/behind-the-great-firewall/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../../../2015/04/behind-the-great-firewall/index.html#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[John Flatley]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2015 17:19:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=57</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>This post is coming to you from behind the Great Firewall. Luckily for me, I&#8217;m staying with Yao&#8217;s friend, Yuming, and he has a VPN that lets us still access things like Facebook and Google. Yesterday, Yao and I got up early and left to get xiao long bao (soup dumplings). These are by far my [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2015/04/behind-the-great-firewall/index.html">Behind the Great Firewall</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">John Flatley</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This post is coming to you from behind <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Great_Firewall">the Great Firewall</a>. Luckily for me, I&#8217;m staying with Yao&#8217;s friend, Yuming, and he has a VPN that lets us still access things like Facebook and Google.</p>
<p>Yesterday, Yao and I got up early and left to get xiao long bao (soup dumplings).<span id="more-57"></span> These are by far my favorite food item I&#8217;ve gotten on the trip so far. I&#8217;m a fan of the pan-fried ones over boiled. Yao says that Shanghai is the only place he&#8217;s been to that has good fried XLBs.</p>
<p>We hopped on the subway and headed to Tianzifang. It&#8217;s a renovated residential area with arts and crafts stores. Despite the modern stores, it still has a traditional feel with its classic architecture.</p>
<div id="attachment_64" style="width: 633px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/04/wpid-wp-1429980119884.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-64" decoding="async" class="size-large wp-image-64" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/04/wpid-wp-1429980119884-623x1024.jpg" alt="Tianzifang" width="623" height="1024" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/04/wpid-wp-1429980119884-623x1024.jpg 623w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/04/wpid-wp-1429980119884-182x300.jpg 182w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/04/wpid-wp-1429980119884-900x1480.jpg 900w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/04/wpid-wp-1429980119884.jpg 1080w" sizes="(max-width: 623px) 100vw, 623px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-64" class="wp-caption-text">Tianzifang</p></div>
<p>For lunch, we headed to the Google office in Pudong. It&#8217;s on the 60th floor of the Shanghai World Financial Center, giving it a great view of the Pearl Tower. After eating, we headed to Nanjing Road and stopped by the Fairmont Peach Hotel, originally the Cathay Hotel. During the early 20th century, it was regarded as the most prestigious hotel in Shanghai and roomed many international celebrities.</p>
<p>Next we headed to the Bund for an iconic photo of Pudong (main picture). Apparently, I look like someone famous because as we were walking along the waterfront I was approached by some women to have my photo taken with them.</p>
<div id="attachment_66" style="width: 633px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-66" decoding="async" class="wp-image-66 size-large" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/04/wpid-wp-1429981013213-623x1024.jpg" alt="" width="623" height="1024" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/04/wpid-wp-1429981013213-623x1024.jpg 623w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/04/wpid-wp-1429981013213-182x300.jpg 182w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/04/wpid-wp-1429981013213-900x1480.jpg 900w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/04/wpid-wp-1429981013213.jpg 1080w" sizes="(max-width: 623px) 100vw, 623px" /><p id="caption-attachment-66" class="wp-caption-text">Paparazzi trying to get some action</p></div>
<p>After posing for some photos, we walked back to Nanjing road to look at the shops and find some weird candy Yao was looking for. We went into the No. 1  Shanghai food store. By No.1 I don&#8217;t mean the best food store in Shanghai. Back in the day, government mandated how things were sold and created separate department-like stores for each type of good. So there was one store for food, another for clothing, and so on. Each branch was given a number which was representative of its size.</p>
<p>As we left the store we were approached by a street vendor who wanted to sell us some fake watches. I had never shopped for fake goods so I thought I&#8217;d give it a try. We were led through a dark alley, through a small door, up some steps barely big enough for my feet, and into someone&#8217;s home. At first, I was pretty sketched out, but the room with the goods was like any normal store. I&#8217;m not really that good at knowing which fakes are the good ones so I decided not to buy anything.</p>
<p>We continued walking along Nanjing road and bought some crafts from a peddler. Out of no where, a man came and tried to snatch the goods out of the sellers hands and pushed him out of the way. Apparently this is how they discourage illegally selling goods on the street. We followed the man for a bit and any time a seller saw him they ran off like frightened children into the alleys. At first it was kind of funny, but I began to feel bad when one lady tried to get her goods back. This is obviously how she makes a living and supports herself.</p>
<p>Up until this point I was wondering where all of the 14 million people in Shanghai were. None of the subway trips had been very full and I didn&#8217;t think there was an extraordinary number of people on the streets. That changed on the subway back to  Yuming&#8217;s place. The terminal was packed with people and we could barely get into one of the subway cars.</p>
<p>Later in the night we headed out to a small Japanese bar/restaurant to meet up with some of Yao&#8217;s high school friends and have a few too many drinks. I was able to find this funny sign in the bathroom:</p>
<p><a href="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/04/wpid-wp-1429980052809.jpg"><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter wp-image-59 size-large" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/04/wpid-wp-1429980052809-623x1024.jpg" alt="wpid-wp-1429980052809.jpg" width="623" height="1024" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/04/wpid-wp-1429980052809-623x1024.jpg 623w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/04/wpid-wp-1429980052809-182x300.jpg 182w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/04/wpid-wp-1429980052809-900x1480.jpg 900w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/04/wpid-wp-1429980052809.jpg 1080w" sizes="(max-width: 623px) 100vw, 623px" /></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>We have one more full day in Shanghai before we leave for Tokyo on Monday.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2015/04/behind-the-great-firewall/index.html">Behind the Great Firewall</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">John Flatley</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../../../2015/04/behind-the-great-firewall/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Big Buddha</title>
		<link>./../../../2015/04/the-big-buddha/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../../../2015/04/the-big-buddha/index.html#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[John Flatley]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2015 15:46:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=49</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Yesterday, Yao and I decided to head over to Lantau Island to see the giant Buddha and monastery. I&#8217;ve really enjoyed taking public transportation in Asia and it starts with the escalators.You think I&#8217;m kidding, but they are at least 30% faster than the ones in the U.S. Next, the subway trains are huge. I&#8217;m [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2015/04/the-big-buddha/index.html">The Big Buddha</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">John Flatley</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Yesterday, Yao and I decided to head over to Lantau Island to see the giant Buddha and monastery. I&#8217;ve really enjoyed taking public transportation in Asia and it starts with the escalators.<span id="more-49"></span>You think I&#8217;m kidding, but they are at least 30% faster than the ones in the U.S. Next, the subway trains are huge. I&#8217;m pretty sure you could fit a Mini Cooper in them. Lastly, unlike Bart, they subway is fast, clean and remarkably quiet.</p>
<p>Once you get to Lantau Island you can either take a bus or a cable car to the sites. These cable cars are similar to a skyline ride at a theme park and give you a great view of Tung Chung Bay and the mountainous terrain.</p>
<p>After 268 steps, we reached the 112&#8242; bronze statue. Although the surrounding area looks traditional, the Buddha statue was actually constructed in 1993. After &#8220;donating&#8221; some money for some Mala beads, we took a look at the monastery and <a href="http://www.discoverhongkong.com/eng/see-do/great-outdoors/outlying-islands/lantau-island/wisdom-path.jsp">wisdom sticks</a>. Neither of us left any wiser considering we couldn&#8217;t decipher the characters on the wooden monuments.</p>
<div id="attachment_44" style="width: 639px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/04/wpid-wp-1429800471070-e1429801404354.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-44" decoding="async" class="size-large wp-image-44" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/04/wpid-wp-1429800471070-e1429801404354-832x1024.jpg" alt="Tian Tan Buddha" width="629" height="774" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/04/wpid-wp-1429800471070-e1429801404354-832x1024.jpg 832w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/04/wpid-wp-1429800471070-e1429801404354-244x300.jpg 244w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/04/wpid-wp-1429800471070-e1429801404354-900x1108.jpg 900w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/04/wpid-wp-1429800471070-e1429801404354.jpg 1131w" sizes="(max-width: 629px) 100vw, 629px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-44" class="wp-caption-text">Tian Tan Buddha</p></div>
<p>We hadn&#8217;t eaten all day and decided to grab food at a local restaurant our Airbnb host recommended. We ended up ordering one of my favorite dishes and one that Hong Kong is well-known for, chow fun. I was pretty surprised that it tasted very similar to the chow fun you can get in the Sunset District in San Francisco. We were still hungry and decided to get some dim sum (main picture) around the corner from our room.</p>
<div id="attachment_45" style="width: 639px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/04/wpid-wp-1429800519197.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-45" decoding="async" class="size-large wp-image-45" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/04/wpid-wp-1429800519197-1024x768.jpg" alt="Eating chow fun. I'm getting better with chopsticks." width="629" height="472" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/04/wpid-wp-1429800519197-1024x768.jpg 1024w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/04/wpid-wp-1429800519197-300x225.jpg 300w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/04/wpid-wp-1429800519197-900x675.jpg 900w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/04/wpid-wp-1429800519197-1280x960.jpg 1280w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/04/wpid-wp-1429800519197.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 629px) 100vw, 629px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-45" class="wp-caption-text">Eating chow fun. I&#8217;m getting better with chopsticks.</p></div>
<p>Later in the day we met up with some of Yao&#8217;s high school friends from Shangai. One of his friends, Grace, has an apartment in the Mid-Levels on Hong Kong island with a great view of the harbor. Yao had requested we go out for some Western Cantonese cuisine, so his friends brought us to Tai Ping Koon. They are famous for their <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Swiss_Wing">Swiss sauce chicken wings</a> that ironically, have nothing to do with Swiss food.</p>
<div id="attachment_51" style="width: 639px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/04/wpid-wp-1429803414923.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-51" decoding="async" class="wp-image-51 size-large" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/04/wpid-wp-1429803414923-1024x576.jpg" alt="wpid-wp-1429803414923.jpg" width="629" height="354" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/04/wpid-wp-1429803414923-1024x576.jpg 1024w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/04/wpid-wp-1429803414923-300x169.jpg 300w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/04/wpid-wp-1429803414923-900x506.jpg 900w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/04/wpid-wp-1429803414923-1280x720.jpg 1280w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/04/wpid-wp-1429803414923.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 629px) 100vw, 629px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-51" class="wp-caption-text">View of Hong Kong from Mid Levels</p></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Yao and I ended our night by grabbing some drinks at a bar in LKF (Lan Kwai Fong), which is Hong Kong&#8217;s night life area. Unfortunately, it was a Wednesday night so not a lot was going on. As for today, it&#8217;s been more food and a flight to Shanghai.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2015/04/the-big-buddha/index.html">The Big Buddha</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">John Flatley</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../../../2015/04/the-big-buddha/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Firsts</title>
		<link>./../../../2015/04/firsts/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../../../2015/04/firsts/index.html#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[John Flatley]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2015 17:58:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=35</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>A ship in the harbor is safe, but that&#8217;s not what ships were made for Yesterday I embarked on my trip to Asia with my old coworker Yao. The first stop is Hong Kong and I have already experienced many firsts: Going through security with TSA Pre✔. I recently signed up for global entry, which also gave me [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2015/04/firsts/index.html">Firsts</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">John Flatley</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>A ship in the harbor is safe, but that&#8217;s not what ships were made for</p></blockquote>
<p>Yesterday I embarked on my trip to Asia with my old coworker Yao. The first stop is Hong Kong and I have already experienced many firsts:<span id="more-35"></span></p>
<p><strong>Going through security with TSA Pre<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/2714.png" alt="✔" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />.</strong><br />
I recently signed up for global entry, which also gave me TSA Pre<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/2714.png" alt="✔" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />. For $100 and a 5 min &#8220;interview&#8221; I got both for 5 years. We all know how much of a pain it is to fly nowadays, mainly because of security checks. If you ask my dad what it was like back in the day, he&#8217;ll tell you he could show up 30 min before his flight with just about anything in his bag and zip through security. That&#8217;s about how awesome it is to have TSA PRE<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/2714.png" alt="✔" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />.</p>
<p><strong>Flying internationally with United.</strong><br />
We flew on a 747-400, the ones with the bubble at the front, and you could tell it was an old plane. There were no individual entertainment monitors, but United makes up for it by letting you stream media to your tablet for free. One thing they could learn from fellow Star Alliance partner Singapore Airlines, is food quality. Their &#8220;sausage&#8221; tasted like a dirty tree branch or fake meat from a post apocalyptic society.</p>
<p><strong>Eating street food.</strong><br />
Hong Kong is well-known for its food, and I was brave enough to try some off the street. For reference, I&#8217;ve gotten sick eating street food in Miami. The area surrounding our Airbnb, La Boutique de Austin, is full of restaurants and street vendors. No picture does the area justice as every corner you turn you are blinded by neon signs. Yao and I decided to stop by a street vendor and try some authentic Cantonese BBQ pork. It was more tender than any I have eaten in the U.S.</p>
<div id="attachment_31" style="width: 574px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/04/wpid-wp-1429636696049.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-31" decoding="async" class=" wp-image-31" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/04/wpid-wp-1429636696049-300x169.jpg" alt="Typical bbq street vendor with pork, duck and chicken liver." width="564" height="316" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/04/wpid-wp-1429636696049-300x169.jpg 300w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/04/wpid-wp-1429636696049-1024x576.jpg 1024w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/04/wpid-wp-1429636696049-900x506.jpg 900w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/04/wpid-wp-1429636696049-1280x720.jpg 1280w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/04/wpid-wp-1429636696049.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 564px) 100vw, 564px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-31" class="wp-caption-text">Typical BBQ street vendor with pork, duck and chicken liver.</p></div>
<p><strong>Meeting a childhood hero.</strong><br />
Hong Kong is also well-known for some famous actors such as Jackie Chan and my personal childhood hero, Bruce Lee. There is a promenade called the Avenue of Stars, which is very similar to the Hollywood Walk of Fame. At the Avenue of Stars you can get a great look at the city skyline across Victoria Harbor. Lining the avenue are star name plates of famous actors and actresses and towards the end there is a famous statue of Bruce Lee.</p>
<div id="attachment_32" style="width: 639px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/04/wpid-wp-1429636734341-e1429640269700.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-32" decoding="async" class="size-large wp-image-32" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/04/wpid-wp-1429636734341-e1429640269700-1024x965.jpg" alt="Me and Bruce Lee" width="629" height="593" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/04/wpid-wp-1429636734341-e1429640269700-1024x965.jpg 1024w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/04/wpid-wp-1429636734341-e1429640269700-300x283.jpg 300w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/04/wpid-wp-1429636734341-e1429640269700-900x848.jpg 900w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/04/wpid-wp-1429636734341-e1429640269700.jpg 1146w" sizes="(max-width: 629px) 100vw, 629px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-32" class="wp-caption-text">Me and Bruce Lee</p></div>
<p>Yao and I ended our night with a few drinks at the local night market.</p>
<p><a href="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/04/wpid-wp-1429636764408.jpg"><img decoding="async" class=" size-large wp-image-33 aligncenter" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/04/wpid-wp-1429636764408-1024x576.jpg" alt="wpid-wp-1429636764408.jpg" width="629" height="354" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/04/wpid-wp-1429636764408-1024x576.jpg 1024w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/04/wpid-wp-1429636764408-300x169.jpg 300w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/04/wpid-wp-1429636764408-900x506.jpg 900w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/04/wpid-wp-1429636764408-1280x720.jpg 1280w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/04/wpid-wp-1429636764408.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 629px) 100vw, 629px" /></a></p>
<p>I&#8217;m already loving this city and can&#8217;t wait to explore more tomorrow!</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2015/04/firsts/index.html">Firsts</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">John Flatley</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../../../2015/04/firsts/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
